Oscar Giovanni Amaya Gomez

Engineer with 9 years of experience working in Java web apps, primarily in the retail industry. I have skills to strengthen the software research and development process, assuming the role of designer and/or solution developer keeping in mind software quality and customers' needs. My career has been oriented to BE solutions.



Bogotá, Colombia Mobile: (+57) 3212567028 E-mail: oamaya0991@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Wizeline, Bogotá: Software Engineer III

October 2021 - Present

- Technical specification of requirements
- Design and development web applications based on Spring Boot
- Integration of applications with services on AWS

La Cadena Retail Solutions SAS, Bogotá: Senior Developer

July 2014 - September 2021

- * Requirements definition with the clients
- Design and development web applications and integration with IBM OS4690
- Management of development teams

La Cadena Retail Solutions SAS, Bogotá: Junior Developer

June 2012 - June 2014

- Web development in Java (Struts 1.2)
- Write DDL DML in different DB platforms like SQLServer, MySql, Oracle, DB2

TRAINING

Universidad de los Ándes, Bogotá: Magíster on Software Engineer

August 2017 - Present

Escuela Colombiana de Ingeniería Julio Garavito, Bogotá: *Systems Engineer*

January 2009 - September 2013

SKILLS

- JAVA
- Spring Boot Framework
- Struts 1.2
- Scrum Framework
- SQL
- Cloud integration

ACHIEVEMENTS

Migration of legacy products to recent technologies and integration with existing applications improving maintainability and performance in customer business processes

Definition of integration alternatives between rules of deployment defined in Terraform and parameterization hosted in the cloud (AWS parameter store)

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (mother tongue)
- English